GOLD measures the upper atmosphere,
which is directly affected by the sun
and what we call space weather.
Scientists are working to better
be able to predict space weather
because it directly affects
the safety of our satellites,
the health of our astronauts,
and the technologies that we
use every day in our life
like GPS navigation.
GOLD will be sitting twenty
two thousand miles above Earth,
which means that it can see
a whole half of the Earth,
all of the Western Hemisphere.
And it will be hovering over one
particular point on Earth,
watching the dynamics
of the atmosphere play out below.
I am excited about this mission
because GOLD will be getting information
about the upper atmosphere
much faster than ever before,
and we'll be able to look
at effects that are more like
the weather that we
experience down here on Earth.
The GOLD and ICON missions will give
scientists the most comprehensive view
we've ever had of the upper atmosphere.